Guide to the Gregory Breit Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Gregory Breit papers
1917-1991
MS 1465
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
49
(66 boxes)
The papers consist of personal and professional correspondence, diaries, reports, data files, writings, printed material, and topical files relating to Gregory Breit's research and teaching career. There are also photographs, biographical information, and files related to his father's design of an anti-submarine attack device in the late 1910s.
Breit, Gregory, 1899-1981
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The papers were transferred to the Yale University Department of Physics from the State University of New York at Buffalo in 1982 and transferred from the Department of Physics to Manuscripts and Archives in 1987. The papers were formally donated to Manuscripts and Archives by Ralph W. G. Wyckoff in 1988. Gift of Faith R. Wyckoff, 2011.
Existence and Location of Copies
Correspondence (1932-1973) and Diaries and Notebooks (1935-1973) are available on microfilm (20 reels, 35mm.) from the American Institute of Physics, New York, NY. HM 211
Conditions Governing Access
Boxes 63-65 of Series III, Additional Material, are restricted for seventy-five years after the date appearing on the document and will be available for research between 2011 and 2050 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
Series I, Correspondence and Series II, Diaries and Notebooks have been microfilmed. Patrons must use FILM HM 211 instead of the originals.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged in three series and one addition: I. Correspondence, 1932-1973. II. Diaries and Notebooks, 1935-1973. III. Additional Material, circa 1929-1980.
Scope and Contents
The Gregory Breit Papers contain personal and professional correspondence, diaries, notebooks, writings, and research project, teaching and conference files which document Breit's research and teaching career. The papers were transferred to Manuscripts and Archives from the Department of Physics, Yale University in 1987. Sixteen linear feet of the 48.5 linear feet of papers are fully processed and arranged in two series. The remaining 32.5 linear feet are preliminarily processed.
I. CORRESPONDENCE
II. DIARIES AND NOTEBOOKS
Series I, CORRESPONDENCE, consists of Breit's outgoing letters, and letters received from individuals and representatives of government agencies, academic institutions, professional associations and scholarly societies, journals, and conferences and symposia. The bulk of the correspondence dates from the 1950s through 1973 and is of a professional rather than personal nature. While there is correspondence dating from the years of World War II within the series, Breit never took possession of his wartime files, which were classified. Routine Yale University and the State University of New York at Buffalo (SUNY-Buffalo) correspondence is not included in the series, but is within the Yale and SUNY-Buffalo material (boxes 58 and 59).
Individuals with whom Breit corresponded extensively include Saraj N. Gupta, McAllister H. Hull, Jr., Allan C. G. Mitchell, H. Pierre Noyes, J. Robert Oppenheimer, Moti L. Rustgi, Edward Teller, Merle A. Tuve, John A. Wheeler, and Eugene Paul Wigner. Institutions represented in the series include the Department of Terrestrial Magnetism of the Carnegie Institution, Lawrence Radiation Laboratory, Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, the National Academy of Sciences, the National Research Council, the National Science Foundation, the U. S. Army Ballistic Research Laboratory, and the U. S. Atomic Energy Commission. Breit's correspondence with an individual may be found under the individual's name as well as under the name of the organization or institution with which he or she was associated.
Correspondence relating to professional recommendations and student and personnel records has been removed from Series I and is restricted. (See Restricted Material below.)
Series II, DIARIES AND NOTEBOOKS, consists of diaries which contain brief notations of professional activities; notebooks which contain entries relating to Breit's lectures and courses; notes pertaining to conferences and meetings Breit attended; and calculations and related notations.
Series I and II were microfilmed in a joint project with the American Institute of Physics as a part of the Institute's series Sources for the History of Nuclear Physics. The 32.5 linear feet of preliminarily processed papers have been roughly sorted and arranged in categories. The preliminarily processed material described below was not microfilmed.
Writings: Reprints of articles by Breit; preprint and reprint mailing lists and requests; manuscripts and typescripts of papers and articles by Breit and others; and referee reports by Breit for the Physical Review.
Data files: Memoranda, notes, and calculations relating to research conducted by Breit and his colleagues; calculations and notes pertaining to preprints and articles of others.
Teaching files: Lecture notes and course syllabi.
Yale University and SUNY-Buffalo files: Routine administrative files regarding the physics departments of the universities, including notes, memoranda, and correspondence. Personnel-related files are restricted.
Research project files: Grant proposals, progress reports, annual reports, and related correspondence. Project account books which contain personnel salary records are restricted.
Conference files: Notes and printed material relating to conferences and symposia attended by Breit.
Notes: Manuscript and typescript notes and internal office memoranda pertaining to Breit's day-to-day professional activities.
Personal files: Curriculum vitae, photographs, lists of publications, and certificates of awards. A diary dated 1959-1962 contains entries regarding Breit's health.
Student files: Student grade sheets, examinations, lab notebooks; files containing memoranda, notes and typescripts relating to Breit's supervision of doctoral students' dissertations. All files are restricted.
Restricted material: Material described above as restricted has been arranged by type of material and placed in boxes 63 through 65. This material is restricted for seventy-five years after the date appearing on the document in order to protect the privacy of the individuals involved.
Series I and II of the Gregory Breit Papers were microfilmed in a joint project with the American Institute of Physics as part of the Institute's series Sources for the History of Nuclear Physics. Researchers who are unable to visit Yale University or the American Institute of Physics may borrow or purchase the microfilm from the Center for the History of Physics, American Institute of Physics:
Center for the History of Physics
American Institute of Physics
335 East 45th Street
New York, NY 10017-3483
Biographical / Historical
Gregory Breit was born on July 14, 1899,in Nickolaev, Russia. He was a student at the School of Emperor Alexander in Nickolaev from 1909 to 1915. He immigrated to the United States with his family in 1915 and became a citizen through the naturalization of his father in 1918.
Breit received the A.B. (1918), the M.A. (1920), and the Ph.D. (1921), from Johns Hopkins University. He was a National Research Council Fellow at the University of Leyden from 1921 to 1922, and at Harvard University from 1922 to 1923.
He began his teaching career in 1923 when he joined the faculty of the University of Minnesota as an assistant professor of physics. From 1924 to 1929, he was a mathematical physicist at the department of terrestrial magnetism at the Carnegie Institution in Washington, D.C. where he initiated experiments in nuclear physics and developed with M.A. Tuve and other colleagues the multi-section high-voltage accelerating tube and made early measurements on nuclear reactions. During several months in 1928, Breit was a resident at the Technische Hochschule in Zurich, Switzerland.
Breit was professor of physics at New York University from 1929 to 1934, and at the University of Wisconsin from 1934 to 1947. He was a research associate at the Carnegie Institution (1929-1944); a member of the Physical Sciences Division of the National Research Council (1932-1933, 1938-1941); a visiting member of the Institute for Advanced Study at Princeton University (1935-1936); and councillor of the American Physical Society (1935-1938).
During World War II Breit was on the staff of the Naval Ordnance Laboratory, Washington Navy Yard (1940-1941), where he developed degaussing methods to protect naval ships against German magnetic mines. In 1942 Breit was named information chief coordinator of the Fast Neutron Project, Metallurgical Laboratory (Manhattan Project), at the University of Chicago, where he was involved in the early development of the atom bomb.
From 1942 to 1943 Breit was a member of the Applied Physics Laboratory at Johns Hopkins University where he conducted research on the proximity fuse which was used to stop the "buzz bomb" attacks on Great Britain and Belgium. He was a member of the Ballistic Research Laboratory at Aberdeen Proving Ground, Maryland as head physicist and member of the director's Scientific Advisory Committee from 1943 to 1945. His war service also included research for the Uranium Committee of the National Defense Research Committee, headquartered at the National Bureau of Standards.
In 1952, before the United States detonated the world's first hydrogen bomb, Breit conducted research at Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, Yale's Sloane Physics Laboratory, and Oak Ridge National Laboratory which proved that a hydrogen bomb explosion would not cause a worldwide chain reaction.
Breit joined the faculty of Yale University as professor of physics in 1947 and was named the first Donner Professor at Yale in 1958. After reaching mandatory retirement in 1968, Breit accepted a position as Distinguished Service Professor at the State University of New York at Buffalo. He continued to conduct research after 1976 as professor emeritus.
A prolific author of scientific articles, Breit was also associate editor of the Physical Review (1927-1929, 1939-1941, 1954-1956, 1961-1963), associate editor of the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences (1951-1960), and consultant to the editor of Il Nuovo Cimento (1964-?).
Breit was elected a member of the National Academy of Sciences in 1939, was made a fellow of the Institute of Radio Engineers in 1945, and of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences in 1951. He was also a fellow of the American Physical Society, the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers, the Physics Society (London), and the Geophysical Society. Breit was the recipient of an honorary Doctor of Science degree from the University of Wisconsin in 1954, the Franklin Medal of the Franklin Institute in 1964, the National Medal of Science in 1967, and the T. W. Bonner Prize of the American Physical Society in 1969.
Gregory Breit married Marjorie MacDill in 1927. They had no children. He died in Salem, Oregon, on September 13, 1981.
Conditions Governing Access
For the portions of the collection that have been filmed, patrons must use HM 211 instead of the originals.
Nuclear physics; Nuclear physics -- Research -- United States; Educators; Physicists; Breit, Gregory, 1899-1981; Gupta, Saraj N.; Hull, McAllister H., 1923-; Mitchell, Allan C. G. (Allan Charles Gray), 1902-; Noyes, H. Pierre, 1923-2016; Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1904-1967; Rustgi, Moti Lal, -1992; Teller, Edward, 1908-2003; Tuve, Merle Antony, 1901-1982; Wheeler, John Archibald, 1911-2008; Wigner, Eugene Paul, 1902-1995; Carnegie Institution of Washington. Department of Terrestrial Magnetism; Lawrence Radiation Laboratory; Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory; National Academy of Sciences (U.S.); National Research Council (U.S.); National Science Foundation (U.S.); State University of New York at Buffalo; U.S. Army Ballistic Research Laboratory; U.S. Atomic Energy Commission; Yale University
- Correspondence, 1932-1973; Series I; 14.5 linear feet (29 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains correspondence arranged alphabetically by name of individual or corporate body. Within each file material is arranged chronologically. Unidentified correspondence is arranged chronologically at the end of the series. Undated material follows dated documents in folders.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Materials in Series I, Correspondence have been microfilmed. Patrons must use FILM HM 211 instead of the originals.
  - Aaron, Ronald, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1, Reel 1U)
  - Abelson, Philip H., 1942, 1944, 1962-1964, 1971-1972, undated (Box 1, Folder 2, Reel 1U)
  - Abramowitz, Milton, 1948-1952, 1954-1956, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3, Reel 1U)
  - Academic Press, Inc., 1947, 1957, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 4, Reel 1U)
  - Academic Press, Inc., 1965-1966, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5, Reel 1U)
  - Adair, Robert K., 1951-1952, 1958, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6, Reel 1U)
  - Addison-Wesley Press, Inc., 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 7, Reel 1U)
  - Ajzenberg, Fay, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 8, Reel 1U)
  - Alberta Symposium on Quantum Chemistry, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 9, Reel 1U)
  - Alder, Kurt, 1955, 1959, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10, Reel 1U)
  - Alex, Brown and Sons, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 11, Reel 1U)
  - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, 1955-1956, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 12, Reel 1U)
  - Allen, W. D., 1955 (Box 1, Folder 13, Reel 1U)
  - Allen Company, Inc., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 14, Reel 1U)
  - Allison, Samuel K., 1945, 1951, 1953, 1956, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 15, Reel 1U)
  - Almqvist, E., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 16, Reel 1U)
  - Alvarez, Luis, 1949, 1951, 1964, 1966, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 17, Reel 1U)
  - Amati, D., 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 18, Reel 1U)
  - Ambassador Hotel, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 19, Reel 1U)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1937, 1951, 1953, 1957, 1964, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 20, Reel 1U)
  - American Association of Physics Teachers, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 21, Reel 1U)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 22, Reel 1U)
  - American Geophysical Union, 1958, 1962-1963, 1968-1970, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 23, Reel 1U)
  - American Institute of Physics, 1937-1938, 1941, 1952-1960, 1962-1964, 1966-1967, 1969, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 24-27, Reel 1U)
  - American Institute for Research, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 28, Reel 1U)
  - American Journal of Physics, 1951-1952, 1968-1969, 1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 29, Reel 1U)
  - American Men of Science, undated (Box 1, Folder 30, Reel 1U)
  - American Nuclear Society, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 31, Reel 1U)
  - American Ordnance Association (Army Ordnance Association), 1944, 1946-1951, 1954, 1956, 1959, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 32, Reel 1U)
  - American Physical Society, 1934, 1941,1946-1947, 1950, 1953-1957, 1959-1962 (Box 2, Folder 33, Reel 1U)
  - American Physical Society, 1964-1965, 1967-1970, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 34, Reel 1U)
  - American Scientist, 1954, 1969-1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 35, Reel 1U)
  - Anderson, Hubert L., 1942, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 36, Reel 1U)
  - Andrews, Dudley J., 1961, 1968, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 37, Reel 1U)
  - Annual Reviews, Inc., ( Annual Review of Nuclear Science ), 1952, 1956-1957, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 38, Reel 1U)
  - Annual Rochester Conference of High Energy Nuclear Physics, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 39, Reel 1U)
  - Antioch College, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 40, Reel 1U)
  - Araki, Gentaro, 1951-1960, 1963-1964, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 41, Reel 1U)
  - Arfken, George, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 42, Reel 1U)
  - Argonne National Laboratory, 1946-1948, 1952-1953, 1955, 1964-1967, 1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 43, Reel 1U)
  - Arndt, R. A., 1964 (Box 2, Folder 44, Reel 1U)
  - Arnold Sommerfeld Centennial Memorial Meeting, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 45, Reel 1U)
  - Ashmore, A., 1962 (Box 2, Folder 46, Reel 1U)
  - Associated Universities, Inc., 1950, 1952, 1957, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 47, Reel 1U)
  - Atomic Energy of Canada Ltd., 1958, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 48, Reel 1U)
  - Atoms for Peace Awards, Inc., 1957, 1960, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 49, Reel 1U)
  - Austern, Norman, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 50, Reel 1U)
  - Australian Institute of Physics, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 51, Reel 1U)
  - Baglin, John E. E., 1971 (Box 2, Folder 52, Reel 1U)
  - Baldin, A. M., 1959 (Box 2, Folder 53, Reel 1U)
  - Banaras Hindu University Department of Physics, 1959-1960, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 54, Reel 1U)
  - Banerjee, Manoj K., 1971 (Box 2, Folder 55, Reel 1U)
  - Bardeen, John, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 56, Reel 1U)
  - Barlow, Robert, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 57, Reel 1U)
  - Barschall, Heinz H., 1947, 1948-1951, 1953-1954, 1958, 1961-1962, 1964-1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 58-60, Reel 2U)
  - Bartlett, James H., 1933 (Box 2, Folder 61, Reel 2U)
  - Bartram, R. H., 1963 (Box 2, Folder 62, Reel 2U)
  - Bates, D. R., 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 63, Reel 2U)
  - Beams, Jesse W., 1950, 1969, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 64, Reel 2U)
  - Bearden, J. A., 1961 (Box 2, Folder 65, Reel 2U)
  - Becker, Richard L., 1966, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 66, Reel 2U)
  - Beekman Tower Hotel, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 67, Reel 2U)
  - Belifante, F. J., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 68, Reel 2U)
  - Benedict, Donald L., 1968 (Box 3, Folder 69, Reel 2U)
  - Benenson, Walter, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 70, Reel 2U)
  - Berkner, Lloyd Viel, 1951-1954, 1956, 1958, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 71, Reel 2U)
  - Beringer, E. R., 1954-1955, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 72, Reel 2U)
  - Berners, E. D., 1957 (Box 3, Folder 73, Reel 2U)
  - Bethe, Hans Albrecht, 1952-1955, 1957-1961, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 74, Reel 2U)
  - Bethe, Hans Albrecht, 1965-1968, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 75, Reel 2U)
  - Bethge, Klaus, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 76, Reel 2U)
  - Biedenharn, Lawrence C., 1952-1962, 1964, 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 77, Reel 2U)
  - Blackwell's, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 78, Reel 2U)
  - Blaker, J. Warren, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 79, Reel 2U)
  - Blair, John S., 1965 (Box 3, Folder 80, Reel 2U)
  - Blatt, John M., 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 81, Reel 2U)
  - Bloch, F., 1934 (Box 3, Folder 82, Reel 2U)
  - Bloch, Ingram, 1952-1953, 1955-1957, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 83, Reel 2U)
  - Bludman, Sidney, 1951-1954, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 84, Reel 2U)
  - Bockelman, Charles K., 1968, undated (Box 3, Folder 85, Reel 2U)
  - Bogan, Alexander, Jr., 1968 (Box 3, Folder 86, Reel 2U)
  - Bogolubov, Nikolai N., 1969 (Box 3, Folder 87, Reel 2U)
  - Bohr, Aage, 1952, 1954, 1957, 1959, 1962, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 88, Reel 2U)
  - Bohr, Niels, 1934, 1953-1954, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 89, Reel 2U)
  - Bonner, Tom W., 1939-1940, 1942, 1947, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 90, Reel 2U)
  - Booth, Norman E., 1968 (Box 3, Folder 91, Reel 2U)
  - Born, Max, 1961, 1969, undated (Box 3, Folder 92, Reel 2U)
  - Borst, Lyle B., undated (Box 3, Folder 93, Reel 2U)
  - Boston Passport Agency, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 94, Reel 2U)
  - Botzian, Rudolf, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 95, Reel 2U)
  - Bouricius, Willard G., 1952, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 96, Reel 2U)
  - Bradbury, Norris E., 1953, 1963-1964, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 97, Reel 2U)
  - Brandow, Baird H., 1965 (Box 3, Folder 98, Reel 2U)
  - Brandt, Richard G., 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 99, Reel 2U)
  - Brasefield, Charles J., 1957 (Box 3, Folder 100, Reel 2U)
  - Brayshaw, David D., 1973 (Box 4, Folder 101, Reel 2U)
  - Bretscher, Egon, 1952-1955, 1958, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 102, Reel 2U)
  - Briggs, Lyman J., 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 103, Reel 2U)
  - Britten, Wesley, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 104, Reel 2U)
  - Brix, Peter, 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 105, Reel 2U)
  - Brolley, John E., 1956-1957, 1967-1968, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 106, Reel 2U)
  - Bromley, D. Allan, 1959-1960, 1965, 1968-1973 (Box 4, Folder 107, Reel 2U)
  - Brookhaven National Laboratory, 1950-1967, 1970-1971, undated (Box 4, Folder 108-110, Reel 2U)
  - Brouwer, D., 1956 (Box 4, Folder 111, Reel 2U)
  - Brown, Gerald E., 1950-1953, 1956-1958, 1962, 1964-1965, 1967-1970, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 112, Reel 2U)
  - Broyles, Arthur A., 1958, 1962, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 113, Reel 3U)
  - Brueckner, Keith A., 1955, 1960-1962, 1967, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 114, Reel 3U)
  - Bryan, Ronald A., 1962-1964, 1966-1967, undated (Box 4, Folder 115, Reel 3U)
  - Buchta, J. W., 1951, 1954, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 116, Reel 3U)
  - Burcham, W. E., 1955, 1957, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 117, Reel 3U)
  - Bureau of Applied Social Research, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 118, Reel 3U)
  - Burhop, E. H. S., 1964-1966, undated (Box 4, Folder 119, Reel 3U)
  - Bush, Prescott, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 120, Reel 3U)
  - Bush, Vannevar, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 121, Reel 3U)
  - Byrne, Frank, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 122, Reel 3U)
  - Cahill, Fred, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 123, Reel 3U)
  - California Institute of Technology, 1961, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 124, Reel 3U)
  - Cameron, A. G. W., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 125, Reel 3U)
  - Camp, Sylvia, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 126, Reel 3U)
  - Canadian Journal of Physics, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 127, Reel 3U)
  - Carnegie Institution of Washington, 1927, 1930, 1932-1935 (Box 4, Folder 128-129, Reel 3U)
    General
    Department of Research in Terrestrial Magnetism
  - Carnegie Institution of Washington, 1936-1937, 1939-1940, 1947-1951, 1965-1967, 1970, undated (Box 5, Folder 130, Reel 3U)
  - Carruthers, P., 1966 (Box 5, Folder 131, Reel 3U)
  - Case Western Reserve University, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 132, Reel 3U)
  - Castillejo, Leonardo, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 133, Reel 3U)
  - Catillon, Philippe, 1966, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 134, Reel 3U)
  - Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 135, Reel 3U)
  - Chalmers, Joseph S., 1967 (Box 5, Folder 136, Reel 3U)
  - Chamberlain, Owen, 1954, 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 137, Reel 3U)
  - Chand, Ramesh, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 138, Reel 3U)
  - Chandrasekhar, S., 1966 (Box 5, Folder 139, Reel 3U)
  - Charleton, E. E., 1938 (Box 5, Folder 140, Reel 3U)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank, 1962, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 141, Reel 3U)
  - Chew, Geoffrey F., 1952, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 142, Reel 3U)
  - Chinchwaokar, S. K., 1963 (Box 5, Folder 143, Reel 3U)
  - Chun, Thee W., 1965 (Box 5, Folder 144, Reel 3U)
  - Citizens Committee for Peace with Freedom in Vietnam, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 145, Reel 3U)
  - Clarendon Press, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 146, Reel 3U)
  - Clarkson College of Technology, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 147, Reel 3U)
  - Clementel, Ezio, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 148, Reel 3U)
  - Cohen, Bernard L., 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 149, Reel 3U)
  - Cohen, E. Richard, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 150, Reel 3U)
  - Cohen, Karl, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 151, Reel 3U)
  - Cohen, Larry Kenneth, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 152, Reel 3U)
  - Cole, Stephen, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 153, Reel 3U)
  - College of William and Mary, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 154, Reel 3U)
  - Collins, George B., undated (Box 5, Folder 155, Reel 3U)
  - Colorado Associated University Press, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 156, Reel 3U)
  - Columbia Radiation Laboratory, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 157, Reel 3U)
  - Columbia University, 1948, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 158, Reel 3U)
  - Columbia University Press, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 159, Reel 3U)
  - Committee for a University, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 160, Reel 3U)
  - Committee to Keep the Republic of China in the United Nations, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 161, Reel 3U)
  - Compton, Arthur Holly, 1958, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 162, Reel 3U)
  - Condon, Edward U., 1938, 1940, 1944, 1946-1947, 1951, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 163, Reel 3U)
  - Conference on High Energy Two-Body Reactions, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 164, Reel 3U)
  - Conference on Particle Reactions and Nuclear Accelerators, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 165, Reel 3U)
  - Conference on Resonant Particles, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 166, Reel 3U)
  - Conference on Theoretical Physics, 1938-1941, 1947-1948 (Box 5, Folder 167, Reel 3U)
  - Congrés International de Physique Nucléaire, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 168, Reel 3U)
  - Connecticut Civil Liberties Union, undated (Box 5, Folder 169, Reel 3U)
  - Consolidated Vacuum Corporation, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 170, Reel 3U)